place.
Their most faithful disciples were the two cart horses, Boxer and Clover.
These two had great difficulty in thinking anything out for themselves.
But having once accepted the pigs as their teachers, they absorbed everything
that they were told and passed it on to the other animals by simple arguments.
They were unfailing in their attendance at the secret meetings in the barn and
led the singing of Beasts of England with which the meetings always ended.
Now, as it turned out, the rebellion was achieved much earlier and more easily
than anyone had expected.
In past years, Mr. Jones, although a hard master, had been a capable farmer.
But of late, he had fallen on evil days.
He had become much disheartened after losing money in a lawsuit and had taken
to drinking more than was good for him.
For whole days at a time, he would lounge in his Windsor chair in the
kitchen, reading the newspapers, drinking, and occasionally feeding Moses
on crusts of bread soaked in beer.
His men were idle and dishonest.
The fields were full of weeds. The buildings wanted roofing.
The hedges were neglected. And the animals were underfed.
June came and the hay was almost ready for cutting.
On Midsummer's Eve, which was a Saturday, Mr. Jones went into Willingdon
and got so drunk at the Red Lion that he did not come back till midday on Sunday.
The men had milked the cows in the early morning and then had gone out rabbiting
without bothering to feed the animals.
When Mr. Jones got back, he immediately went to sleep on the drawing-room sofa
with the News of the World over his face so that when evening came, the animals
were still unfed.
At last, they could stand it no longer.
One of the cows broke in the door of the store-shed with her horn and all the
animals began to help themselves from the bins.
It was just then that Mr. Jones woke up.
The next moment, he and his four men were in the store-shed with whips in
their hands lashing out in all directions.
This was more than the hungry animals could bear.
With one accord, though nothing of the kind had been planned beforehand, they
flung themselves upon their tormentors.
Jones and his men suddenly found themselves being butted and kicked from all sides.
The situation was quite out of their control.
They had never seen animals behave like this before and this sudden uprising of
creatures whom they were used to thrashing and maltreating just as they
chose frightened them almost out of their wits.
After only a moment or two, they gave up trying to defend themselves and took to their heels.
A minute later, all five of them were in full flight down the cart-track that led
to the main road with the animals pursuing them in triumph.
Mrs. Jones looked out of the bedroom window, saw what was happening,
hurriedly flung a few possessions into a carpet bag and slipped out of the farm by another way.
Moses sprang off his perch and flapped after her, croaking loudly.
Meanwhile, the animals had chased Jones and his men out onto the road and
slammed the five-barred gate behind them.
And so, almost before they knew what was happening, the rebellion had been
successfully carried through.
Jones was expelled, and the Manor Farm was theirs.
For the first few minutes, the animals could hardly believe in their good fortune.
Their first act was to gallop in a body right round the boundaries of the farm,
as though to make quite sure that no human being was hiding anywhere upon it.
Then, they raced back to the farm buildings to wipe out the last traces of Jones's hated reign.
The harness room at the end of the stables was broken open. The bits, the
nose rings, the dog chains, the cruel knives with which Mr. Jones had been
used to castrate the pigs and lambs were all flung down the well.
The reins, the halters, the blinkers, the degrading nose bags were thrown onto
the rubbish fire, which was burning in the yard.
So were the whips.
All the animals capered with joy when they saw the whips going up in flames.
Snowball also threw onto the fire the ribbons with which the horses' manes and
tails had usually been decorated on market days.
>> "Ribbons should be considered as clothes, which are the mark of a human being.
All animals should go naked."
>> When Boxer heard this, he fetched the small straw hat which he wore in summer
to keep the flies out of his ears and flung it onto the fire with the rest.
In a very little while, the animals had destroyed everything that reminded them of Mr. Jones.
Napoleon then led them back to the store-shed and served out a double
ration of corn to everybody, with two biscuits for each dog.
Then they sang Beasts of England from end to end seven times running.
And after that, they settled down for the night and slept as they had never slept before.